

Umair Khan

Nationality: Pakistani Date of birth: 11/09/2001 Gender: Male

Complex Complex Comp

○ WhatsApp Messenger: +923317272005

in LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/umair-khan-b4b227240

Q GitHub: https://github.com/SE-Umee

Website: https://se-umee.github.io/Umair-Khan-Portfolio/

• Home: Shahbari kala Bannu, 28100 Bannu (Pakistan)

• Work: Islamabad (Pakistan)

ABOUT ME

I'm a hardworking and ambitious individual with great passion. I am a graduate as a Software Engineer at UST, Bannu. I have excellent communication skills, enabling me to communicate with a wide range of people. I am seeing a full-time job in which I can put my knowledge and experience, ultimately benefiting the operations of the organization that I work for.

WORK EXPERIENCE

React Native Developer

Gitrex Technologies Islamabad [05/09/2022 - 14/02/2023]

City: Islamabad | Country: Pakistan

React Native Developer

InfinityBits Islamabad [16/02/2023 – 30/11/2023]

City: Islamabad | Country: Pakistan

React Native Developer

dnet [01/12/2023 - 15/10/2024]

City: Riyadh | Country: Saudi Arabia

React Native Developer

AppFlow Creations [18/10/2024 - Current]

City: New York City | Country: United States

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

SSC

BISE Bannu, KPK [22/06/2016]

Address: Township, Bannu Township, Bannu, Khyber Pakhtunkhwa, 28100 Bannu (Pakistan) | Field(s) of study: Science

HSSC

BISE Bannu, KPK [02/08/2018]

Address: Township, Bannu Township, Bannu, Khyber Pakhtunkhwa, 28100 Bannu (Pakistan) | Field(s) of study: Computer Science

Bsc Software Engineering

University of Science & Technology Bannu, KPK [14/10/2022]

Address: Bannu, KPK, 28100 Bannu (Pakistan)

DIT

Khyber Pakhtunkhwa Board of Technical Education [12/07/2018]

Address: Phase 5 Hayatabad, Peshawar, Khyber Pakhtunkhwa, 25000 Peshawar (Pakistan)

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Mother tongue(s): Pashto

Other language(s):

Urdu English

LISTENING C2 READING C2 WRITING C2 LISTENING C1 READING C1 WRITING C1

SPOKEN PRODUCTION C2 SPOKEN INTERACTION C2 SPOKEN PRODUCTION C1 SPOKEN INTERACTION C1

Levels: A1 and A2: Basic user; B1 and B2: Independent user; C1 and C2: Proficient user

DIGITAL SKILLS

Mobile development / HTML5/CSS / Git / GitHub / Object-Oriented Programming / Data Structure / FireBase / MS Office (MS Word, MS PowerPoint, MS Excel) / GitLab

React Native

React - React Native / React Hooks, React Router, React Redux / JavaScript / Redux / Redux-Toolkit / Tailwind CSS / CS S / API Intergration / Google Map Api / Firebase (Push notifications) / Payment integration / Google Pay / Apple Pay

Android

XML / Java

PROJECTS

LocalChaow (Food App) Expo App

Open Local Chow and find yummy food near you, prepared by local farmers and home cooks!

Become a Local Chow seller yourself! It's easy and legal. No fees, permits, or licenses are required. Just take a few pictures of your food, set your price and that's it!

Ami's Choice

Amischoice makes online grocery delivery and grocery shopping fast and easy. Get groceries delivered to your doorstep and order the best products, quick meal solutions, incredible new products, and exclusives. It is an online mini-mart delivery with so much more, from Fresh Deals that help you save big to convenient delivery windows that work around your schedule.

Fast

"Fast: Your Ultimate Fitness Companion

Achieve your fitness goals with Fast, the all-in-one fasting and fitness app. Customize your fasting schedule, track your progress, and stay motivated by joining challenges. Whether you're fasting for health or fitness, Fast is your partner in reaching your wellness goals. Start your journey today and experience the power of fasting with Fast!"

Motmaena User App

Motmane is an educational app where users can purchase courses and participate in live sessions with specific consultants. Additionally, users have the opportunity to directly communicate with these consultants through video calls and messages.

Motmaina Consultant App

Motmaena Consultant is a doctor app. This app allows doctors to upload their lectures, manage patient appointments, create prescriptions, and communicate with patients via SMS, audio calls, and video calls.

Tejara

This mobile accessories app provides a diverse range of products, including hands-free devices, AirPods, chargers, and more. In addition, the app offers convenient services such as dryer rentals and starter hire to enhance your overall experience.

[Current]

MAS-Dallas

Muslim American Society (MAS)

Giveaway Insel

Giveaway Insel, is an innovative mobile app that transforms how you exchange and discover giveaway items in your community. Whether you want to declutter your space or find something new, Giveaway Insel makes it easy, rewarding, and environmentally friendly.

Sensebod

Education app with Human and Al mentor

VIP Wholesale

VIP Wholesale is an eCommerce app for in-store and wholesale shopping, offering easy browsing, ordering, bulk purchasing, and real-time inventory updates.

Plus One Distribution

Plus One Distribution is an upcoming eCommerce app specializing in Nicotine Pouches, Smoke, Supplements, Vape Juice, IR, and Vaporizers, offering a seamless shopping experience for customers.

Books App

Online books purchase the app

Mobile Grocery App

I have done my final year project in React Native and Firebase. This project are consist of 3 mobile apps (customer app, vendor app and admin panel). The admin panel is developed in Flutter. In this project, Customers can buy

daily groceries from the nearest registered shops.

HOBBIES AND INTERESTS

Sports

Traveling

